Anton Lysenko

Head of Group of Yandex. Metrika Interfaces Development at Yandex. Ukraine

Location: Kyiv, Ukraine
Cell: +38 066 787-31-76
E-mail: mail@antonlysenko.com
Web: https://antonlysenko.com/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonlysenko/

Born in Jul, 1982

Spoken, technical English. Russian, Ukrainian native speaker

Summary

10+ years of professional work experience and expertise in web-development. From feature-rich eye candy web-sites at Art. Lebedev's Studio to high-loaded web services at Yandex.

My main line of work is providing solutions and the highest level technical direction in the development of new or existing web-applications to solve basic to complex problems or enhancements, writing clean, reliable and readable code as well.

Still, got excellent learning skills, work well within a team as well as individually, attentive to details. Understanding of simplicity and efficiency.

Technical Profile

- JavaScript (ES5/ES6), Web API, HTML5, ReactJs, RxJs
- Full stack frontend with NodeJs
- Designing REST APIs
- Development of sophisticated single-page web applications and UIs
- · Organizing team and development processes
- · Web Usability
- Building Git-based CI processes
- Code version control with Git
- NoSQL and SQL based data layer implementation

Education

1999 – 2005 National Technical University of Ukraine "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute", Specialist's degree in Radio-engineering.

Career History

Aug 2014 - Present

Senior Frontend Developer, Head of Group at Yandex.Ukraine Yandex.Metrika, AppMetrica, Yandex.Audience

Oct 2006 - Jul 2014

Web-developer, Senior Web-developer at Art. Lebedev Studio (Ukraine) https://www.artlebedev.ru/lisenko/